<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: links | Joe Ross]]></title>
  <link href="http://joeross.github.io/blog/categories/links/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://joeross.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-02T02:42:46-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://joeross.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Joe Ross]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Larry Lessig fighting for campaign finance reform with Mayday PAC]]></title>
    <link href="http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/07/29/larry-lessig-fighting-for-campaign-finance-reform-with-mayday-pac/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/07/29/larry-lessig-fighting-for-campaign-finance-reform-with-mayday-pac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://nytimes.com/2014/07/29/us/spending-big-to-fight-big-donors.html">Larry Lessig fighting for campaign finance reform with Mayday PAC
</a></p>

<p>Lawrence Lessig&rsquo;s <a href="https://mayday.us">Mayday PAC</a> is using the very system it decries to attempt to bring that system down. In other words, Lessig et al are hijacking the virus (the influence of big donors on American politics via election contributions) to deliver the vaccine (funding for politicians committed to proposals which would limit big political contributions).</p>

<p>If you support the cause, be heartened: Lessig <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2013/09/27/226834651/record-label-picks-a-fight-over-copyright-with-the-wrong-guy">likes to fight</a>, and is good at it.</p>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t support the cause, it&rsquo;s probably time to start taking Mayday seriously. Your candidate&rsquo;s job may depend on it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook is not free]]></title>
    <link href="http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/07/22/facebook-is-not-free/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-22T15:51:41-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/07/22/facebook-is-not-free</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://ift.tt/1wQ7jYw">Facebook is not free</a></p>

<p>If you use Facebook, this article is a must-read. It’s now common knowledge Facebook is always watching and analyzing how you use the service. But the breadth and depth of the company’s participation in the data brokering economy is staggering. The worst part? You literally signed up for it.</p>

<p>Facebook obviously doesn’t charge its users money, but the mere act of creating a profile affirmatively grants the company total access and usage rights over everything you do on the site. It even shares its data about you with data brokerage firms whose business model is monetizing you.</p>

<p>This is all stuff I have personally known and accepted for a long time, but as the ability to easily aggregate dossiers on anyone and everyone increases, it’s more important than ever to educate yourself and those you care about. Facebook is not free, and in fact it’s worth asking whether the price most people pay by clicking a harmless-looking “I agree” button is really worth it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why we don't speak up at work]]></title>
    <link href="http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/07/16/why-we-dont-speak-up-at-work/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-16T09:28:30-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/07/16/why-we-dont-speak-up-at-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://ift.tt/1roiuqV">Why we don&rsquo;t speak up at work</a></p>

<p>This piece by Claire Lew at Signal v. Noise doesn’t exactly fit into my general topics of law, technology and design, but it’s so important I that feel obligated to share it. I mention in my article about the role of metrics in editorial strategy that I’ve been present for some poor decisions and didn’t speak my mind.</p>

<p>Claire’s post explains exactly why I failed to speak up, and it’s an important read whether you’re a manager or not. Unlike more navel-gazing, hand-wavy articles in the management advice realm, she actually offers some practical advice.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For the NSA, we are the haystack]]></title>
    <link href="http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/07/06/for-the-nsa-we-are-the-haystack/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-06T18:38:22-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/07/06/for-the-nsa-we-are-the-haystack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://ift.tt/1xyAP7v">For the NSA, we are the haystack</a></p>

<p>Barton Gellman, Julie Tate and Ashkan Soltani, reporting at the Washington Post:</p>

<blockquote>
  Nine of 10 account holders found in a large cache of intercepted conversations, which former NSA contractor Edward Snowden provided in full to The Post, were not the intended surveillance targets but were caught in a net the agency had cast for somebody else.
</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook COO Sandberg apologizes for emotional contagion experiment]]></title>
    <link href="http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/07/04/facebook-coo-sandberg-apologizes-for-emotional-contagion-experiment/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-04T08:19:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/07/04/facebook-coo-sandberg-apologizes-for-emotional-contagion-experiment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://ift.tt/1riQbfR">Facebook COO Sandberg apologizes for emotional contagion experiment</a></p>

<ol type="a">
<li>Jai Krishna, reporting on the reaction of Facebook Chief Operating Officer Sheryl Sandberg to the outcry over the company’s experiment on the emotions of nearly 700,000 unwitting users:</li>
</ol>


<blockquote>
  We take privacy and security at Facebook really seriously because that is something that allows people to share” opinions and emotions, Sandberg said.
</blockquote>


<p>The telling part about Sandberg’s reaction is that those who take privacy and security seriously don’t have to say very often, if at all.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
