<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Links | Joe Ross]]></title>
  <link href="http://joeross.github.io/blog/categories/links/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://joeross.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-14T23:06:19-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://joeross.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Joe Ross]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Systemic Failure of Modern Hiring Practices]]></title>
    <link href="http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/09/13/failure-modern-hiring/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/09/13/failure-modern-hiring</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://qz.com/258066/this-is-why-you-dont-hire-good-developers/">The systemic failure of modern hiring practices</a></p>

<p>Laurie Voss, in a piece about technical hiring that is easily applied to the legal field and hiring more generally, on asking applicants questions to which they almost certainly don’t know the answer:</p>

<blockquote><p>The weakest candidates will try to waffle or make wild guesses. This is a terrible sign, firstly because it never works, and secondly because they thought that it would. [ &hellip; ] Strong candidates say “I don’t know” as soon as they hit their limit, and may start asking questions. The very strongest candidates say “but if I had to guess” and then attempt to extrapolate.</p></blockquote>

<p>Yup. And what’s more, most interviewers or hiring managers who ask such counterproductive questions are actually looking for the waffles and the wild guesses. They invariably want to see someone who can obfuscate without sacrificing an air of omniscience.</p>

<p>It’s an astounding feat of self-sabotage, and it makes it difficult for the truly intelligent among us (like myself, all arrogance aside…) to make an impression among the din of bloviating thought-sheep.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Privacy Advocates, Tech Companies Nudge Congress to Protect ‘abandoned’ E-mails]]></title>
    <link href="http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/09/12/privacy-advocates-tech-companies-congress-abandoned-emails/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/09/12/privacy-advocates-tech-companies-congress-abandoned-emails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/wp/2014/09/11/privacy-advocates-tech-companies-nudge-congress-to-protect-abandoned-e-mails/">Privacy advocates, tech companies nudge Congress to protect ‘abandoned’ e-mails</a></p>

<p>The Email Privacy Act would prevent the government from using mere administrative subpoenas to access email older than 180 days. The distinction, included in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stored_Communications_Act">Stored Communications Act </a>, was based on the need for users to access and download email from a service provider&rsquo;s servers. The logic was that if someone hadn&rsquo;t downloaded their email in six months or more, they had effectively abandoned it.</p>

<p>Of course, things are no longer that simple in the age of constant synchronization and push notifications on mobile devices.</p>

<p>Previously:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://constantandendless.com/links/grover-norquist-on-proposed-update-to-electronic/">Grover Norquist on proposed update to Electronic Communications Privacy Act</a></li>
<li><a href="http://constantandendless.com/links/ecpa-amendment-would-require-warrant-even-for-email/">ECPA amendment would require warrant even for email older than 6 months</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[7th Circuit Strikes Down Gay Marriage Bans in Wisconsin and Indiana]]></title>
    <link href="http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/09/05/7th-circuit-gay-marriage/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/09/05/7th-circuit-gay-marriage</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://bigstory.ap.org/article/court-rules-against-gay-marriage-bans-2-states">7th Circuit strikes down gay marriage bans in Wisconsin and Indiana</a></p>

<p>The legal momentum favors universal application of the fundamental right of two consenting adults to marry, but that doesn’t make each ruling any less exciting.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Listen: The Lawfare Podcast Discusses Zombies in the Context of International Law and National Security]]></title>
    <link href="http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/09/03/lawfare-podcast-zombies/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/09/03/lawfare-podcast-zombies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.lawfareblog.com/2014/08/lawfare-podcast-episode-89-bone-crushing-zombie-action/">Listen: The Lawfare Podcast discusses zombies in the context of international law and national security</a></p>

<p>If you’ve ever wondered how international law, laws of war and national security policy might be applied to a zombie apocalypse scenario, listen to episode 89 of The Lawfare Podcast.</p>

<p>The law and policy discussed are real and interesting but the tongue-in-cheek analysis is wonderfully entertaining.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Larry Lessig Fighting for Campaign Finance Reform With Mayday PAC]]></title>
    <link href="http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/07/29/larry-lessig-fighting-for-campaign-finance-reform-with-mayday-pac/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://joeross.github.io/blog/2014/07/29/larry-lessig-fighting-for-campaign-finance-reform-with-mayday-pac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://nytimes.com/2014/07/29/us/spending-big-to-fight-big-donors.html">Larry Lessig fighting for campaign finance reform with Mayday PAC
</a></p>

<p>Lawrence Lessig&rsquo;s <a href="https://mayday.us">Mayday PAC</a> is using the very system it decries to attempt to bring that system down. In other words, Lessig et al are hijacking the virus (the influence of big donors on American politics via election contributions) to deliver the vaccine (funding for politicians committed to proposals which would limit big political contributions).</p>

<p>If you support the cause, be heartened: Lessig <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2013/09/27/226834651/record-label-picks-a-fight-over-copyright-with-the-wrong-guy">likes to fight</a>, and is good at it.</p>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t support the cause, it&rsquo;s probably time to start taking Mayday seriously. Your candidate&rsquo;s job may depend on it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
